<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Random | $whois andyregan]]></title>
  <link href="http://andyregan.net/blog/categories/random/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://andyregan.net/"/>
  <updated>2013-01-09T17:16:18+00:00</updated>
  <id>http://andyregan.net/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Andrew Regan]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Fix Mac OS X DNS Failure on UPC Router]]></title>
    <link href="http://andyregan.net/fix-mac-os-x-dns-failure-on-upc-router/"/>
    <updated>2010-07-17T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andyregan.net/fix-mac-os-x-dns-failure-on-upc-router</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>About a week ago, I upgraded my MacBook Pro to OS X 10.6.4. Since then, I've had trouble with the internet
connection <strong>only</strong> from my house and <strong>only</strong> on my MBP. Sometimes the connection would work fine, but
most of the time Firefox/Safari would only load the first couple of pages and then new pages would start to
time out.</p>

<p>Since I could ping/view a site by going to the server's IP address directly, the issue appeared to be with
the MBP resolving <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Domain_Name_System">DNS</a>. DNS is how your computer translates a human readable URL such as
<strong>andyregan.net</strong> to a machine readable IP address.</p>

<p>Since the problem was <strong>only</strong> with my UPC connection (router is Cisco EPC2425), I thought changing DNS
provider to <a href="http://code.google.com/speed/public-dns/">Google</a> or <a href="http://www.opendns.com/">OpenDNS</a> might do the trick. Alas, the new DNS servers would work for the
first few pages and then pages started timing out again.</p>

<p>After poking around the (extremely limited) options on the UPC router, I noticed that there were a ton of
firewall blocks for the 192.168.1.0/24 network over the last week. Devices connecting to the router, such
as my MBP, are assigned IP addresses within this range.</p>

<p>On closer inspection, I discovered that the router's firewall was blocking the MBP from the DNS servers
for <strong>LAN-side UDP Flood</strong>. I turned off the router's firewall and restarted it. Et voila! Bob's your
uncle.</p>

<p>My guess is that the firewall blocks must be due to some change in DNS behavior since the last OS X
update. Posting here to save some poor soul the heartache. It's important to note that turning off your
router's firewall is at your own risk.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Shoot First Questions Later]]></title>
    <link href="http://andyregan.net/shoot-first-questions-later/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-29T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andyregan.net/shoot-first-questions-later</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><a href="http://www.digitalmediaforum.net/event_profile.php?id=292"><img class="center" src="/images/posts/shoot-first-questions-later/sfql_graphic.png"" title="SFQL Graphic" alt="SFQL Graphic"> </a></p>

<p><a href="http://www.digitalmediaforum.net/event_profile.php?id=292">SFQL</a> is a different approach to business networking. Break the ice by playing a few LAN games and having a laugh. Afterwards, head to a nearby pub for some refreshments and have a chance to chat with like-minded people in the tech industry from Galway.</p>

<p>It's happening May 6th from 7pm in Squareyes, Forster St (near Eyre Square). The cost of gaming is &euro;6.</p>

<p>This is a <a href="http://www.digitalmediaforum.net/about.php">Digital Media Forum</a> event. The idea was born at the last Digital Media Breakfast in Galway and has been put together thanks to <a href="http://twitter.com/antonmannering/">@antonmannering</a> and <a href="http://www.squareyes.com/">Squareyes</a>.</p>

<p>Promises to be good craic! Join via <a href="http://www.digitalmediaforum.net/event_profile.php?id=292">the event page</a> so we'll have some idea of numbers. Thanks! :)</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[I Can Haz Job?]]></title>
    <link href="http://andyregan.net/i-can-haz-job/"/>
    <updated>2009-04-26T00:00:00+01:00</updated>
    <id>http://andyregan.net/i-can-haz-job</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<div class="video-container">
<iframe width="640" height="360" src="http://www.youtube.com/embed/qTjAu03V9pY?feature=player_embedded" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div>


<p>According to RTE there should be plenty of work for me and my classmates when we graduate. Good to hear. (As Forrest Gump would say, "One less thing, you know?".) Unfortunately, from my experience so far this year I don't think it's going to be quite as easy to get a good job in ICT as RTE suggests.</p>

<p>The dramatic reduction in the number of people studying computer sciences courses since the dot-com bust has been no more obvious than in my own course. At the start of this decade, GY350 Information Technology was very much in demand, with hundreds of students and Round 1 CAO points regularly over 400.</p>

<p>Today, there's <strong>nine</strong> of us in final year.</p>

<p>What caused the continuous slump in applicants? According to a <a href="http://www.forfas.ie/publications/2008/title,951,en.php">report</a> published last year by Forf&aacute;s, the national policy advisory body for enterprise and science, the mammies and guidance councilors of Ireland share a large part of the blame.</p>

<p>When the numbers of ICT jobs started to fall sharply and graduates found themselves competing to find work the mammies of Ireland took heed. The word was out that the "<em>computhers</em> game" was a lame duck.</p>

<p>Nay not so. While fewer positions were available, the revenue generated by the ICT industry continued to grow and after 2004 the number of people employed in ICT began to steadily grow again. However, the stigma of the bust was not forgotten.</p>

<p>Personally, I know a number of people who wanted to study IT but were told "sure there's no jobs in that" and "wouldn't you study civil engineering and make a fortune like young Gombeen down the road?".</p>

<p>Now we're told Ireland doesn't have enough IT graduates to meet demand. RTE reports that "50% of software hires in Dublin are from abroad" at a time when 4000 people (including many college graduates) are applying for 280 jobs in Ikea.</p>

<p>Aside from worries about job security, I also think that people have a poor understanding of the type of work that an IT student will do once they graduate. When I'm asked what I'm studying in college, I generally have to brace myself for the inevitable "Oh, you're doing IT? Is there much work fixing computers?". (Usually followed by a request to fix a broken printer or laptop. o_0 )</p>

<p>One of the main recommendations of the Forf&aacute;s report is "better communication of career opportunities and skills needs of the ICT sector ". I think a good effort is now being made by the government and 3rd level institutions to change people's perceptions of ICT. Hopefully, this will lead to more applications over the coming years.</p>

<p>An unexpected side affect of the drop in demand for ICT courses was an increase in the drop out rate. The points for my course bombed from 385 in 2001 to 225 in 2002. The points began to steadily climb again, but in the proceeding years I know that some people applied for the course purely based on the low points requirement. They struggled with the course material and work load. Many failed and either repeated or dropped out.</p>

<p>Other similar courses such as Electronic Engineering experienced the same problems.</p>

<p>All this should be good news to me, right? Less competition and all that? Unfortunately, my pending departure from 3rd level education is coinciding with probably the most dramatic hic-up in the Irish and global economy.</p>

<p>Already, a number of companies well-known for hiring IT graduates have suspended hiring for the rest of the year due to "the current macro-economic environment". I didn't hear <em>that</em> mentioned in the RTE report.</p>

<p>I also think some companies are continuing to advertise for jobs not knowing if they will be able to actually take on new hires, probably because they don't want to seem weak in the current climate.</p>

<p>I'm not expecting to fall out of my degree onto a smorgous board of opportunity waiting to snap me up. (Prove me wrong, world. Prove me wrong.) In fact, I think I'm going to have to really sell myself to land a good job where I'll be competing against people that are out of work and who have a few year's experience under their belts.</p>

<p>Are there plenty of jobs out there? I'm sure there is, but definitely not to the extent reported by RTE last Thursday.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Random Bits]]></title>
    <link href="http://andyregan.net/random-bits/"/>
    <updated>2009-03-08T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <id>http://andyregan.net/random-bits</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>I haven't come across anything that deserves a full post this week, so here's 5 interesting technologies I've come across recently:</p>

<ul>
<li><a href="http://www.cyberciti.biz/tips/understanding-linux-unix-umask-value-usage.html">umask</a>

<ul>
<li>How to set default permissions when creating files in linux</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.dohop.com/">DoHop.com</a>

<ul>
<li>Find Cheap Flights</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://crazybob.org/twubble/">Twubble</a>

<ul>
<li>Friends of Friends for Twitter</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.winterwell.com/software/jtwitter.php">JTwitter</a>

<ul>
<li>Java Library for the Twitter API</li>
</ul>
</li>
<li><a href="http://www.twitterlocal.net/">TwitterLocal</a>

<ul>
<li>Find tweets by location</li>
</ul>
</li>
</ul>


<p>And here's some more randomness:</p>

<p><em>Switching to VoIP</em> by Ted Wallingford is very related to that 4IF1 are currently studying in Real Time Systems. Chapter 6 in particular.</p>

<p>When ordering books from Amazon, do not screw around during the ordering stage unless you want two of the same book. <em>/me hangs head in shame</em>.</p>

<p>The 3 wireless dongle works perfectly in Ubuntu.</p>

<p><a href="http://worldofgoo.com/dl2.php?lk=demo">World of Goo</a> is a very addictive game.</p>

<p>Finally, congrats to Emma Conway for her win in the NUIG Student Union elections. Unfortunately, Pofla didn't get in.  I hoarded as many whispa's as I possibly could to prevent their dispersal to the general populace to no avail.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
